Guide to the Ernesto Galarza Papers, 1936-1984
Department of Special Collections
- Subject files, 1923-1978, Series 4
  - Subseries H: Geographical Locations, 1936-1966
    - Immigration (illegal), "Braceros y Mojados, Negacion de Mexico," n.d. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Immigration (illegal), correspondence, 1948-1959 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1947-1950 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1952 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1953 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Immigration (illegal), newsclippings, 1955-1964 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Immigration (illegal), notes and miscellany, 1948-1961 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Immigration (illegal), press releases, 1951-1954 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Immigration (illegal), statements and reports, 1947-1954 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Migrant children, 1948-1961 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Migrants, 1945-1967 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Migrants, newsclippings, 1947-1964 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Poverty relief programs, newsclippings, 1948-1949 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Poverty relief programs, newsclippings, 1950-1960 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Public Law 86-257, Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "Right-to-Work" Law (California Proposition 18), 1957-1959 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "Right-to-Work" Law (California Proposition 18), newsclippings, 1957-1960 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Right-to-Work" Law (California Proposition 18), publicity, 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Dr. Paul S., articles and testimony, 1943-1971 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Texas Pecan Shellers' Strike, 1938-1939 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, "Farm Labor" (newsletter), 1947-1967 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, newsletters, press releases, 1957-1968 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, statements and reports, 1952-1967 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - U.S. President's Commission on Migratory Labor, "Migratory Labor Notes," 1958-1962 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - U.S. President's Commission on Migratory Labor, statements, reports, newsclippings, 1949-1962 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - U.S. House of Representatives, farm labor issues, 1949-1964 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Senate, farm labor issues, 1952-1964 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Senate, farm labor issues, hearings on agricultural policy, ca. early 1950s (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Wage Stabilization Board (National and Region 12/California), regulations and reports, 1951-1952 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Wages, correspondence, 1949-1962 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Wages, field notes and wage stubs, 1942-1954 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Wages, minimum wage and benefits, 1949-1967 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Wages, NFLU, wage questionnaire, 1950-1954 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Wages, newsclippings, 1948-1951 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Wages, newsclippings, 1952-1964 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Wages, notes, 1944-1959 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Wages, sample contracts (non-NFLU/NAWU), 1923-1970 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Wages, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, regulations, reports, 1945-1960 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Wages in California, 1945-1960 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Wages in the United States, 1948-1959 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I: Other Subjects, 1929-1978
    - Alianza Federal de Pueblos Libres and New Mexico land seizures, 1967-1970 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Alviso, movement against annexation, newsletter, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies, 1942-1963 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Bibliographies, 1966-1971 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Bibliographies, 1972-1973 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies, 1974-1976 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Bibliographies, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Carta Editorial (newsletter), 1964-1966 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Chicano culture and acculturation, 1958-1974 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Chicano culture and acculturation, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Chicano culture and acculturation, newsclippings, 1966-1973 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Church programs, 1950-1970 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Discrimination, reports and statements, 1950-1971 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Discrimination, stereotyping of Mexican-Americans (in the media), 1967-1970 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Education, bilingual, 1962-1978 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Education, bilingual, California Assembly Subcommittee on Bilingual Education, AB2284, 1972-1976 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Education, general, 1957-1978 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Education, Mexican-American educators, 1965-1975 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Education, Mexican-American studies programs, California State College, Los Angeles, 1968-1970 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Education, Mexican-American studies programs, miscellaneous colleges, 1969-1971 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Education, Mexican-American studies programs, San Fernando Valley State College, 1968-1971 56 5 Education, Mexican-American studies programs, San Jose State College, 1967-1976 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Education, Mexican-American studies programs, University of California, Berkeley, Los Angeles, Riverside, San Diego, 1969-1973 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Education, scholarships and grants, 1965, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Education, statements and reports, 1965-1967 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Education, statements and reports, 1968-1970 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Education, statements and reports, 1972-1978 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Education, statements and reports, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Education, student unrest, newclippings, 1966-1970 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Health of Mexican-Americans, reports, proposal, 1954-1972 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Housing, reports, proposal, newsclippings, 1964-1971 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Knowlton, Dr. Clark, papers and speeches, 1962-1966 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Madrid, Arturo, papers and articles, 1972-1974 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Mexican economy, articles from Comercio Exterior, financial data, 1941-1961 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Mexican economy, newsclippings, 1945-1959 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Mexican economy, newsclippings, 1960-1973 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Mexicans in the United States, newsclippings, 1941-1959 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, 1940-1942 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, 1943 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, 1944 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, 1945-1946 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, 1948-1955 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Mexicans in the United States, reports, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Mexicans in the United States, term papers, Claremont College, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Nava, Dr. Julian, papers, resume, political platform, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Poems by Mexican Americans, 1967-1970 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Police treatment of Mexican Americans, 1967-1970 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Politics, 1954-1974 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Politics, newsclippings, 1949-1971 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Population statistics, 1960-1971 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Poverty, articles, 1963-1968 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Poverty, articles, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Poverty, articles by S. Michael Miller, et. al., 1963-1969 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Poverty, newsclippings, Jan.-June, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Poverty, newsclippings, July-Dec., 1965 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Poverty programs, Community Action Program (C.A.P.), general, 1965-1966 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Poverty programs, Community Action Program (C.A.P.), Los Angeles Co. Schools, Proposal IV, ca. 1965 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Poverty programs, Community Action Program (C.A.P.), workbook, Office of Economic Development, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Poverty programs, East Central Area Welfare Planning Council (Los Angeles), 1963-1965 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Poverty programs, Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, War on Poverty Report, ca. 1965 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Poverty programs, Home Education Livelihood Program (H.E.L.P.), New Mexico, 1967, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Poverty programs, Los Angeles Co., papers, notes, newsclippings, ca. 1963-1966 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Poverty programs, Manpower Opportunities Program (M.O.P.), reports, proposal, testimony, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Poverty programs, miscellaneous federal programs, 1964-1974 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Poverty programs, newsclippings, 1963-1969 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Poverty programs, Pascua Village Project (Arizona), 1970 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Poverty programs, Project S.E.R. (Service, Employment, Redevelopment), newsletters and program proposal, 1966-1971 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Poverty programs, Youth Opportunities Board/Economic and Youth Opportunities Agency (YOB/EYOA), correspondence, memos, publicity, 1964-1966 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Poverty programs, Youth Opportunities Board/Economic and Youth Opportunities Agency (YOB/EYOA), "Joint Powers Agreements Establishing EYOA," "History of YOB/EYOA," 1964-1966 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Poverty programs, Youth Opportunities Board/Economic and Youth Opportunities Agency (YOB/EYOA), notes and drafts, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Poverty programs, Youth Opportunities Board/Economic and Youth Opportunities Agency (YOB/EYOA), statements, reports, 1965-1966 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Salazar, Ruben, articles, 1963, 1969-1970 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Poverty programs, information concerning death of, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Sleepy Lagoon Case, 1929-1944 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Community Organization Monitoring Education, "Citizens' Critique," 1976 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Community Organization Monitoring Education, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, administrative complaint, Apr., 1975-May, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, administrative complaint, June, 1976-June, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, administrative complaint, Aug., 1977-July, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, administrative complaint, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, audit, 1976-1977 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, California non-English-speaking and limited-English-speaking data, 1976-1977 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, financial records, 1975-1976 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, minutes, reports, 1973-1977 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, Rene Cardenas, 1974-1977 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, search for director, staff, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, teacher training, 1975-1978 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, Title VII proposal, 1974-1977 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, Title VII proposal, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, San Jose Unified School District, budget printouts, Mar., Apr., Nov., 1976 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, 1970-1974 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, agendas, 1975-1976 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, curriculum materials, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, inventory, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, notes, 1975-1976 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, "Temas Escolares," 1975-1978 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, termination, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Studio Laboratory controversy, Studio Laboratory, termination, 1976 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - United States immigration policy, 1964-1974 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Voting, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Whitney Foundation Opportunity Fellows, 1970 (Box 64, Folder 12)
- PHOTOGRAPHS/GRAPHIC MATERIALS, 1936-1970, Series 5
  The final series consists of photographs and graphic materials. There are eighty-two matted photographs, documents, and graphic materials which were prepared for a television program about the DiGiorgio Fruit Corporation strike. There are photographs of braceros taken by Galarza at recruiting stations in Mexico and at processing centers on the U.S.-Mexican border. Other photographs show migrants and migrant housing in the San Joaquin Valley, DiGiorgio strike activities, field workers, and early Southern Tenant Farmer Union and National Farm Labor Union meetings and leaders.
  - Assassination attempt on James Price, DiGiorgio Strike, May 17, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Braceros, living and working conditions, ca. 1949-1957 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Braceros, recruitment and processing procedures, ca. 1950s (1) (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Braceros, recruitment and processing procedures, ca. 1950s(2) (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Corona, Bert, Msgr. Gerald Fox (Chancellor, Santa Rosa Catholic Diocese), Eduardo Lopez, ca. 1970 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Families of Chualar Bus Accident victims, ca. 1963-1964 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Migrant housing, ca. 1950s (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - National Farm Labor Union meeting, Salinas (?), ca. 1948-1949 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Olivas, Olly, Chicano '70 Huelga, ca. 1970 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers Union, living and working conditions in the South, ca. 1940s (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers Union, leaders and meetings, ca. 1936-1945 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - "Spiders in the House" television program, KNBC Los Angeles, mounted photographs numbered 5-25 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - "Spiders in the House" television program, KNBC Los Angeles, mounted photographs numbered 26-64 (Box 65, Folder 13)
- OVERSIZE
  - Braceros at processing center and working in the fields, (3 photographs mounted on 1 board) (Folder 1)
  - DiGiorgio Strike, (3 photographs mounted on 1 board) (Folder 2)
  - Migrant workers (?), (2 photographs mounted on 1 board) (Folder 3)
  - "Spiders in the House" television program, KNBC Los Angeles, mounted photographs, documents, diagrams, artwork, numbered 1-82 (Folder 4)